抱歉  哥们  等我会吧
sorry, mate. I gotta.
给你  孩子
Here you are, son.
那你在这多久了
so, how long have you been here, then?
我靠了  16年了
Shit...16 years!
- 那么久了啊  - 是啊  很久了
-Yeah? That long? -Yeah, it's been a while.
你住哪里啊
Where are you living?
我跟雷住一起
I'm with ray.
他把车库收拾了  我就住车库了
He fixed up his garage, so I'm in there.
- 舒服吗  - 舒服啊
-Is it comfy? -Yeah.
冬天冷夏天热有时候
Gets a bit hotter and colder sometimes.
估计是没有做隔热层  但是你懂的
'cause I don't think it's insulated, but, you know.
我有自己的地方住了啊
I've got my own space.
我还能多见见雷的女儿
And I get to see a bit more of ray's daughter.
- 他还有女儿呢 - 是啊
-He's got a daughter? -Yeah. Yeah.
布里特  布里特妮
Brit...Brittany.
她多大了
How old is she?
9 岁了
Nine.
雷怎么样啊
How is ray?
挺好的
yeah, good.
他挺好的
He's...He's good.
布鲁斯找你
Brucey needs ya.
怎么了
What's going on?
- 我被卡住了  - 什么意思
-I'm stuck. -What do you mean?
我被卡在椅子里了  出不来了
In the fucking chair. I can't get out of it.
别冲我摇头啊
Don't shake your bloody head at me.
又不赖我
It's not my fault.
好吧  抓他胳膊
Alright. Grab his arm, will you?
抓咯吱窝
Under the armpit.
数到三就往上抬啊  1  2  3
Alright, count of three. One, two, three.
妈的谢了
Bruce: Thank fuck for that.
我他么还以为我要死在这椅子上了呢
Thought I was gonna die in the fucking thing.
那可不
Yeah. If only.
对啊  被困住了啊
Yeah, get stuffed.
- 挺好的吧  - 挺好
-Alright? Steady? -Alright. Yeah.
- 谢谢你来看我  - 嗯
-Ok. Thanks for coming. -Yeah.
希望不久之后下次再见吧
I'll see you again soon, eh? Hopefully.
- 今天很开心  - 爱你啊
-Good to see ya. -Love ya.
我也爱你
Yeah, love you.
走吧
Come on.
回头见
Dad: See you soon.
帮我个忙  大个
need a favour, big fella.
我一个朋友  凯特・哈尔  听说过吗
Mate of mine. You heard of kate hall?
凯特・哈尔
Kate hall.
她是先锋报的一个记者
She's a journo at the 'herald'.
负责犯罪故事的
She covers their crime stuff.
她要写一本书  真实犯罪的书
She's writing a book. Like, a true crime book.
想找素材
And she's looking for stories.
你能不能跟她聊一聊
Wondering if you might wanna have a chat with her.
我有什么好处
What's in it for me?
你帮我个忙啊
You'd be doing me a favour.
帮帮忙啊  这是我一个老朋友的女儿了
Come on, mate. It's an old mate's daughter.
他这么多年也帮过我不少呢
He's done a couple of favours for me over the years,
我也希望还个人情啊
it'd be good to return the favour.
不要
Nuh.
别这样啊  我是作为朋友请你帮忙啊
Mate, come on. I'm asking a favour as a friend here.
不要啊
No.
谢了啊
Thanks.
你知道吗  本来我不打算提这事的
You know what? I wasn't gonna mention this, but...
但你知道
..Do you have any idea
达沃罗斯那件事  你给我惹了多少麻烦吗
what you put me through with that davros shit?
什么
What?
达沃罗斯那件事
The davros bullshit.
你知道那是我女婿的哥哥吧
You know that was my son-in-law's brother, right?
你知道你给我惹了多少事吗
Do you know the trouble that shit caused me?
那人他么的想杀我啊
He tried to fucking kill me.
我知道啊  但我
I know that, but I had...
因为这是  我女婿半年没搭理我
My son-in-law, he didn't speak to me for six months.
真给我找了不少事啊
Caused heaps of friction, alright?
那他么又不是我的错啊
Well, it's not my fuckin' fault!
你让我跟那人聊聊  我聊了啊
You asked me to sit down with the guy and I did.
我知道你聊了  我也很感激  但是他么的
I know you did, mate, and I appreciate that, but shit!
你他么又不是帮我忙啊
Not like I ask you for heaps of favours, you know?
- 嘿  - 嘿你好吗
-hi. -How you going?
- 我是凯特  - 很高兴认识你
-I'm kate. -Nice to meet you.
假设你好奇  我就是凯特啊
-In case you were wondering. -
从这边进来吧
uh, come through.
你家很漂亮
Ray: Nice house.
谢谢啊
Thanks! Yeah.
- 我喜欢这老房子  - 我也是
-I like the old joints. -Yeah, me too.
比新房子更有品位啊
They've got more character than new houses.
- 是啊  - 你要喝点什么吗
-Yeah. -Uh, hey, do you want a drink?
啤酒  水  什么的
Do you want a beer, a glass of water or something?
可以来杯茶啊
Ray: Wouldn't mind a cup of tea.
好的  什么茶
Ok, sure. What kind?
- 你有伯爵茶吗  - 好的  有的
-Have you got any earl grey? -Yeah. Yeah.
那你是在哪里长大的呢
So, where'd you grow up?
距离悉尼开车四小时一个地方吧
About four hours out of sydney.
- 是吗  - 对  在一个农场里
-Oh, yeah? -Yeah, on a farm.
我可以问问是在哪里吗
Mmm! Do you mind my asking where?
你可以问啊
I don't mind you asking.
好吧  是什么农场呢
Right. Um, what kind of farm was it?
- 奶牛场  - 好吧
-Just a dairy farm. -Right.
那你童年幸福吗
Did you have a happy childhood?
还行吧
It was alright.
你想再详细一点说下吗
Did you wanna elaborate maybe a bit on that?
你的书是写什么的
So, what's your book about?
差不多就是罪犯吧
Criminals, pretty much.
我采访过几个人了
Yeah, I mean, I've interviewed a few people so far
就是讲讲自己的故事
and it's just people telling their stories.
我能理解  你会有点防备
Look, I understand if you're a little bit cagey about this,
不愿意都告诉我
and I totally get it.
不过呢
But, um...
我就是想让你炸掉
..I just want you to know that
你不希望我写进去的东西  绝对不会写的
nothing's gonna go in the book unless you're happy with it,
我就是想让你能跟我畅所欲言
so I just want you to, you know, feel comfortable to talk to me.
好吧
Alright.
好  那你介意我录音吗
Cool. Um, do you mind if I record?
不介意
No, it's alright.
- 真的吗  - 好
-Sure? -Mmm.
好的
Ok.
就放那边
I'll just put that there.
那你想不想先说一下
So maybe, I don't know, do you wanna start with
你是怎么开始干这行的呢  比如第一个活儿什么的
about how you got into it - your first job, maybe?
你说的活儿是指什么
When you say 'job', what do you mean?
- 你口中的活儿是什么意思  - 你第一份
-What do you mean, 'job'? -Well, your first...
我说不好  杀人吧  我是说
I don't know, hit. I mean...
谁告诉你我杀人的
Who told you I do hits?
弗雷迪跟我说的  说你
Well, that's what freddy told me, that you'd...
稍微聊了聊
..Talk about that a little bit.
抱歉  我可能会错意了
I mean, sorry, I might have misunderstood that.
我都没意识到  就是弗雷迪说的
I didn't realise that... That's just what freddy said.
所以我才把你叫来
and that's kinda why I got you here,
因为我就想在书中写这种事
'cause that's the sort of stuff I wanna talk about in the book.
恶心
'moist'.
嗯  对
Ray: Yeah, true.
恶心
Moist.
这件不错
-Mmm. -That's a good one.
我奶奶  在我小时候
Yeah. My grandmother, when I was a kid,
她常做茶饼
she used to make this teacake,
那是真的恶心
and that was really moist.
她还在上面放肉桂
she used to put cinnamon on the top of it.
挺好的吧
Lovely. Lovely.
好的  茶饼
Ok. Teacake.
- 茶饼  - 好的
-Teacake. -Right.
阑尾切除术
'appendectomy'.
- 阑尾切除术  -是啊
-'appendectomy'? -Yeah.
阑尾切除术  阑尾切除术  那是啥
Appendectomy. Appendectomy. What's that?
你不知道阑尾切除术是啥
You don't know what appendectomy is?
不知道
No.
就是把你的阑尾切除掉
It's where they take your bloody appendix out.
把阑尾拿掉是吧  我知道的
Take your appendix out. No, I knew that.
你肯定知道的啊
Yeah, sure you did. Yeah.
女式内裤
'panties'.
'panties'?
你说得不像  妞说起来才像
Not when you say it. Like, when a chick says it.
她说的话  就是脱掉我的内裤  这样
When she says, like, "oh, take off my panties!"
这是好词呢
that's a good word. Moist panties.
- 恶心的内裤  - 嗯
-Moist panties? -Yeah.
你这还真是超常发挥了啊
You've outdone yourself, haven't you?
多谢夸奖
Thank you very much.
都会用你最喜欢的两个词造句了
Put two of your favourite words together in a sentence.
- 你知道的  - 很好
-Yeah, well, you know... -Very good.
- 多像作家  - 那必须的
-Quite the wordsmith. -Yeah. Yeah, you are.
- 你觉得如何  - 我挺喜欢的
-What do you reckon? -Yeah, nah. I like it.
摸摸看
Feel that.
我去  这么锋利
Shit. Sharp!
那鱿鱼真不错  兄弟
Gary: And it was good calamari, mate.
新鲜的那种  不是冷冻的烂货
Like, fresh. Fresh as. Not the frozen shit.
你从鱼贩手里买来后
You know, the shit you get from the fishmongers.
但等我把它扔冰箱的时候
But what happened was is that when I put it in the fridge,
我就原封不动放里面了
I've left it in the bag that I've bought it in.
嗯
Yeah.
所以等我想做的时候
So when I've gone to cook it,
鱿鱼都已经在冰箱里放好几天了
it's been in there for a couple of days
然后我给拿出来了
and I've taken it out.
- 真他妈臭  - 是啊
-Fuck it stunk. -Yeah.
臭到家了
Just rank.
臭味弄得满屋子都是
It's just gone all through the house.
我买来的时候要是知道
What I shoulda done, when I bought it,
会放好几天  我就应该
if I was gonna leave it in there for a couple of days,
应该把鱿鱼切好  洗干净
I should have tipped it out, washed it thoroughly,
放在保鲜袋里  放一个新塑料袋里
put it in a fresh plastic bag, a new plastic bag,
然后再丢冰箱里去  你懂的
then whacked it in the fridge and then, you know,
可能有机会
probably would have had a chance
再多保存几天
at lasting a couple more days, you know?
但你知道当时那鱿鱼超脏
But it stewed in its own juices
还流了一堆水么
and its own filth, you know?
所以鱿鱼变质  我只能给扔了
So...So it went off and I had to chuck it out,
臭气熏天  这一斤鬼东西  烦死我了
and it was, like, a kilo of the shit which, you know, bummed me.
不过最让我烦的还是
But what really bummed me
之前我曾看过关于大自然的一些文献
is I was watching one of those nature docos
有一些关于章鱼的
and they had a bit on octopuses
就是生命周期一类的东西
and, like, their life cycle and shit.
我都不知道  不过
And I didn't know this, but...
你知道章鱼是怎么产子的吗
Do you know how octopuses have babies?
雌性章鱼
The female octopus
要怀孕  对吧
gets pregnant, right?
很明显
Obviously.
然后她把卵产到一块岩石上
And she lays eggs underneath a rock, right?
然后她看着这些卵
And then she guards it.
不吃不睡
Doesn't eat, doesn't sleep,
就用那些触手在卵上扫来扫去
and just moves her tentacles over the eggs.
月复一月  知道么
For months and months and months, right?
然后等卵孵好的时候
And just as the eggs hatch,
你知道会怎样吗
you know what happens?
它死了吗
She dies?
它死了
-She dies. -Mmm.
所以我就再也不吃鱿鱼了
So I won't be eating calamari anymore.
鱿鱼是乌贼是吧
Calamari's squid, isn't it?
什么
What?
不是
No.
等等
Hold on.
对  鱿鱼是乌贼  不是章鱼
Yeah, calamari's squid, mate, not octopus.
所以我可以吃鱿鱼咯
So I can eat calamari?
吃去啊
Go for it.
好了
Gary: Alright, then.
历史上有多少钢结构的建筑
How many steel-framed buildings in history
因大火倒塌了
have collapsed due to fire?
- 我不知道  - 有三栋  全是在911那天
-I don't know. -Three, all on 9/11.
- 就俩  - 不对  是仨
-Two. -No, three.
双子塔算俩
You got the twin towers,
然后还有第三栋建筑
and there was a third building.
有两个是被飞机撞毁的  另一个不是
Two were hit by a plane, one wasn't hit by a plane.
那是7号楼  距离大道有几百米
That's building 7, a couple of hundred metres down the road.
那栋楼在不到五秒内就塌了
And that fell a few hours later in under five seconds.
他们说那栋楼是因为
And they say it collapsed
被双子塔的残骸砸中
because it got hit from debris from the twin towers
然后着了火
and then it started a fire
所以才塌的
and that's what caused it to fall.
但控制爆破拆除专家
But controlled demolition experts
说这是一次控制爆破
say it was a controlled demolition.
- 你对讲机开了吗  - 开了
-Got your radio on? -Yeah.
- 好  一会见  - 好
-Alright. See you in a bit. -Alright.
注意点蛇啊
Watch out for snakes!
是  我知道  我
Yeah, I know, I...
快点  狗狗
C'mon, girl!
快点  起来
go on, get up!
不  扔那  快点  我们走了
No, leave that. Come on, let's go.
狗狗快点
Come on, girl.
快点  后面去  后面去  后面去
come on, girl.  round the back. Round the back.
快点
Come on!
扔那吧
leave that.
维尼
Vinnie!
- 干什么  - 快跑
-What? -Run!
哦  妈的
Oh, shit!
追上他 给我他妈的追上他
Get him! Fuckin' get him!
嘿  我来了  妈的
hey, I'm on my way.  fuck.
快点  开车  开车  开车
go! Go, go, go, go, go!
操
fuck!
你被打中了吗
Are you hit?
- 不  我没事  - 你怎么样
-Nah, I'm good. -How'd you go?
啊  不太好
Uh, not too good.
快点  快点  快点
Come on, come on, come on, come on!
走吧
Go.
然后杰克走到了外面
"and so jack went outside
开始爬那根豆茎
"and started to climb the beanstalk.
他爬呀爬  一直爬到了天上  爬进了云里
"he climbed up to the sky through the clouds
他看见了一座美丽的城堡
"and saw a beautiful castle."
他怎么能爬到云里去呢
how could he climb to the clouds?
呃  可能他特别的健壮
Uh, he must have been really fit.
他看见了城堡  走了进去
"so he saw the castle and went inside."
他为什么要走进去呢
why did he go inside?
因为那个城堡很漂亮啊
Well, it was a nice-looking castle
所以他想进去看看
and he just wanted to check it out.
但那样做是不对的
But that's not right.
你不能就那么走进别人家的城堡
You can't just go inside other people's castles like that.
是啊  听着  我觉得这故事对你来说可能有点低幼了
Yeah, look, I think you might be a bit old for this story.
你想听别的书吗
Do you wanna read something else?
不  你接着讲吧  我喜欢听
No, keep going. I like it.
好吧  杰克听见了一个声音  飞 飞 缶 发
Ok. "so jack heard a voice. 'fi, fi, fo, fum!'
杰克躲进了一个碗柜里
"jack ran into a cupboard to hide
一个巨人走进了屋子  坐了下来
"just as an enormous giant came into the room and sat down.
在桌子上有一只母鸡  还有架金色的竖琴
"on the table, there was a hen and golden harp.
下蛋  巨人说
"'lay!' said the giant.
那只母鸡下了个蛋  那个蛋
"the hen laid an egg. It was made...
居然是金子做的
"..Of gold.
奏乐  巨人说
"'sing!' said the giant.
竖琴开始自己弹奏起来  很快巨人就睡着了
"the harp began to sing. Soon the giant fell asleep.
于是杰克从碗柜里跳出来
"so jack jumped out of the cupboard.
他抱上那只鸡  拿起竖琴  向门口跑去
"he took the hen and the harp and he ran for the door."
- 等一下  他把鸡偷走了  - 怎么了
-wait - he stole them? -What do you mean?
为什么要拿走鸡和竖琴啊
Why'd he take the hen and the harp?
- 我不知道  - 但那是盗窃啊
-I don't know. -But that's stealing.
随你怎么说吧  突然竖琴发出声音了  主人  救救我们
Anyway. "suddenly, the harp sang, 'help, master!'
巨人醒来了  大喊道  飞  飞  缶  发
"the giant woke up and shouted, 'fi, fi, fo, fum!'
杰克继续跑  然后从豆茎上开始往下爬
"jack ran and started climbing down the beanstalk
那个巨人在他后面  追的很紧
"and the giant chased after him, hot on his tail.
等杰克到了地面上  他向上看了一下
"when jack reached the ground, he looked up
他看见巨人很快就要到了
"and he saw the giant coming fast,
于是他从柴堆上拿了把斧子
"so he grabbed an axe from the woodpile
然后开始砍那个豆茎
"and started to chop at the beanstalk.
砍了五下  豆茎就掉到了地上
"after five chops, the beanstalk crashed to the ground
那个巨人就死了
"and the giant was slayed."
- 被杀了  - 嗯嗯  是的  杰克杀了他
-slayed? -Mm-hm. Yeah, he killed him.
- 他杀了他  - 嗯
-He killed him? -Mmm.
他在后面追他  所以
He was chasing after him, so...
没错  但是他从巨人那偷东西了啊
Yeah, but he stole from him.
巨人只是想拿回自己的母鸡而已
The giant was just trying to get back the hen
但杰克却杀了他
and he murdered him.
哦  我落下一页
oh, I missed a page.
第二天  警察来找杰克
"so the police visited jack the next day
于是他因为盗窃和谋杀罪被捕了
"and they arrested him for theft and murder
然后他这辈子就在监狱里度过了
"and he went to jail for the rest of his life.
结局了
"the end."
我一点都不喜欢这个故事
I don't like that story at all.
是吗  我也不太喜欢
Yeah, I'm not a big fan of it either.
太可怕了  可怜的巨人
It's terrible. The poor giant.
我想这个故事教给我们的道理是
Well, I guess the moral of the story is,
不要盗窃  不能杀人
you know, don't, uh, steal, don't murder,
否则你这辈子就只能在监狱里待着了
or you'll go to jail for the rest of your life.
好吗  所以不要那么做
Ok? So don't do it.
这故事可真烂
That story sucks.
嗯  是啊
Mmm. It does.
好了  安安
Alright. Night-night.
晚安
Goodnight.
你读过杰克和豆茎的故事吗
you ever read 'jack and the beanstalk'?
很久以前读过  怎么了
A long time ago. Why?
杰克真不是个东西
Jack was a piece of shit.
为什么这么说
Why do you say that?
他爬上了豆茎是吧
Well, he climbs the beanstalk, right?
是啊
Yeah.
他走进了那个巨人的城堡
He goes into the giant's castle,
偷走了竖琴
steals the bloody harp,
偷走了那只下金蛋的大鹅
steals the goose that lays the golden egg.
- 对  - 偷东西
-Yeah. -Steals it.
然后还跑了
Runs off.
于是巨人去追他
So the giant goes after him,
想把自己被偷走的东西拿回来
trying to get back all the shit that jack stole.
对啊
Yeah.
然后当那个巨人从豆茎上往下爬的时候
And while he's climbing down the beanstalk...
杰克就把豆茎砍断了
..Jack chops it down
把那个巨人给杀死了
and fuckin' murders him!
真不是个东西
What a cunt!
抓住一颗流星  放进你的兜里
* catch a falling star and put it in your pocket
别让它的光消退
* never let it fade away
抓住一颗流星  放进你的衣兜里
* catch a falling star and put it in your pocket
中间人先生下集简介
你在部队的时候  还有你现在做的事
When you're in the army and what you do now
有什么不同吗
It's... feeling any diffrence?
我知道他是你朋友  但他得滚蛋了
No I know his your mate, but he's got go.
你女儿呢  如果你出了什么事她肯定会受不了的
What about your daughter. I'm sure she will be devastated if something happened to you.
你的工作危险吗
Is your job dangerous?
不  不怎么危险
No. Not really. No.
我在部队里还得过奖章呢
You know I get medals in the army.
杀手还得奖章呢
Can't imgane hitman get medals?
不是  但我得了好几块呢
Nuh. Pretty piled bit though.